collages.net 2007-06-29

# Collages.net: Total Workflow and Printing Solution for Professional Photographers

|  |  |   
---  
| 

|  Privacy Statement

Collages.net®, recognizes and respects the importance of maintaining the privacy of our photographers, color labs, event guests and other customers, who are all considered registered members (“Members”) and users and has therefore established this Privacy Policy. Below we describe why we gather information from you, what information we collect, how we collect it, what we use the information for and how you can instruct us if you prefer to limit the use of that information. This Privacy Policy is part of the Terms of Use, which governs your use of our web site located at Collages.net (the “Web Site”). The Web Site is owned by Collages.net, Inc. (the “Company”). By visiting Collages.net, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy notice and agree to receive our current privacy policies through our web site.

**Note:** You must be 18 years or older to register as a member or use Collages.net®. 

**Why do we gather information?**

Since our inception, Collages.net® has consistently provided our customers, Members, and users with quality goods and services, excellent customer service, access to useful information, and an overall pleasant interactive experience. We gather personal information to allow us and certain third parties to communicate with you, to process your orders, to provide an enhanced and more personalized interactive shopping experience and to inform you, and your gift and message recipients, of special offers and discounts. These discounts may be offered by third parties, some of which may be independent and not under the control of Collages.net. 

**What information do we gather?  
**  
The information that Collages.net® may collect includes, but is not limited to:  
  
---  
  
  * Name
  * Address
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Title (gender)
  * Birth date
  * Billing information (credit card number, expiration date and billing address)
  * Occasion type (birthday, Mothers day, etc.)
  * Products purchased
  * Any relevant promotion code and information
  * Gift and message recipient's name, address, telephone number, email address, and any other information you provide to us
  * IP address, equipment and browser information - Collages.net® keeps your IP address, equipment and browser information confidential and uses it only to help diagnose problems with our server, to generate internal statistics, and to administer the Website.

We receive and store certain types of information automatically whenever you interact with us. For example, like many web sites, we use “cookies,” and we obtain certain types of information when your web browser accesses Collages.net. A number of companies offer utilities designed to help you visit web sites anonymously. Although this may interfere with and limit our ability to provide you with the services Collages.net offers, we want you to be aware that these tools exist. Collages.net does not warrant the effectiveness of these utilities, and does not represent that we will be able to process your requests or provide services to you should you use such a utility.

**When do we collect information?**

Collages.net® collects personal information online when:  
  
  * you register to become a member of Collages.net® or any other partner services
  * you use our services to store, share, and/or print your pictures online
  * you make online purchases
  * you submit questions or comments to us
  * you participate in online surveys
  * you participate in online forums, chats, bulletin boards, discussion groups
  * you participate in online promotions, premiums, sweepstakes or contests
  * you request that we send information to your friends, family and colleagues

This information is collected through our Web Site and emails. Information you enter might be collected even if you cancel or do not complete the intended use, registration, or order process.  
  
**Note:** If you opt-out from receiving further promotional emails from us, we will not share any of your information with any third parties, including our Affiliates.

**What are "cookies" and how does Collages.net® use them?**

Cookies are small pieces of information stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive, at a web site's request. Collages.net® cookies do not contain any personal information and are used for these reasons: (1) cookies allow us to keep track of the pictures you upload and download; (2) cookies allow us to remember you when you login to the places on our site which require Membership; (3) to remember your country and language preferences; (4) to help us understand the size of our audience, traffic, and bandwidth patterns;(5) to manage and present site information; (6) to deliver information specific to your interests; and (7) to manage site information and pictures displayed on your computer.

**How we use the information we collect about you?**

We use information we collect to:  
  
  * communicate with you
  * to process, fulfill, and follow up on your orders
  * register you in programs
  * create and maintain accounts
  * answer your e-mail
  * send information that you request
  * send friends, families and colleagues information on your behalf
  * to provide an enhanced and more personalized interactive shopping experience
  * to inform you, and your gift and message recipients, of offers and discounts from Collages.net® or other web sites and partners.

In addition, we may periodically make such information (except for credit card number and expiration date, unless you consent otherwise), including aggregated information, personally identifiable information with third party businesses and affiliates for the purpose of direct mail, email marketing and telemarketing.  “Affiliates” are those persons or entities directly or indirectly controlling, controlled by, or under common control with the Company.  You may instruct us not to share personal information about you that you have provided to us with third parties by following the instructions provided below. A Successor to our business is not considered to be a third party for these purposes (see below). 

In the event of a merger, consolidation, or sale or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets or business of the Company by, with, or into another company (a "Successor"), one of the assets which would generally be transferred is the information we collect from our customers, Members, and users. However, the use of this information by any Successor would still be governed by the terms of this Privacy Policy, as amended from time to time, including any amendment after such transaction, and you will continue to have the right to opt-out of sharing your information with third parties. 

We may disclose any information you provide to us (i) when we believe disclosure to be appropriate to comply with any law, regulation, or governmental or law enforcement request, or to comply with judicial process; (ii) if such disclosure is necessary or appropriate to operate this Web Site or to process any orders or registrations or to conduct any promotions, contests, or sweepstakes you participate in; (iii) to protect the rights or property of the Company, its Affiliates,, users, customers, recipients, Members, Sponsors, Providers, Licensors, or Merchants (as such terms are defined in the Terms of Use). 

Please note that any personal information you reveal or post on one our public forums (as defined in the Terms of Use), such as a message board, chat room, discussion group, folder, survey, contest, sweepstakes, user review and rate forum, and all User Submissions, are not protected by this Privacy Policy and may be collected, shared and used by us or with third parties, including to contact you. Information you give out or post on our public forums you disclose at your own risk. 

Portions of the Web Site (such as our Member registration and guest/event login screen) may require registration and log-in processes in which you will need a user ID and password (collectively, the “Password”). Any Password provided to you will be the exclusive property and confidential information of the Company and may be used by you solely for your individual use of this Web Site. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any Password provided to you. All activities that occur using your Password are your responsibility, whether or not authorized by you. You agree to immediately notify us of any unauthorized use of your Password or accounts. 

**Consent to Transfer**

Collages.net® is operated in the United States. If you are located in the European Union or elsewhere outside the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using the Web Site or providing us with your information, you hereby consent to this transfer. In addition, if you provide data to us about other individuals (such as your message recipients), you agree that you have obtained consent from each such individual to the submission and processing of such information under the terms of this Privacy Policy, including without limitation the transfer of such data to the United States. Although we will collect and use your information only as stated in this Privacy Policy, laws generally applicable to the protection of personal data in the United States may not be as stringent as those in some users’ home jurisdictions. 

**Links**

Collages.net® wants you to be aware that when you click on links and/or ad banners that take you to third-party web sites, you will be subject to the privacy policies and terms of use of those third party web sites, not ours. While we support the protection of privacy on the Internet, we cannot be responsible for the actions of third parties. We encourage you to read the posted privacy statement and user terms and conditions whenever interacting with, and prior to providing any personal information to, any other web site.

**Your Security**

If you place an order our Web site encrypts your credit card number you submit prior to transmission over the Internet using secure socket layer (SSL) encryption technology. This technology works best when the site is viewed using Microsoft's Internet Explorer® or Netscape Navigator®. However, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Although we make reasonable efforts to safeguard your personal information once we receive it, we cannot warrant the security of information you transmit to us. 

If you prefer not to have us provide personal information about you to third parties (other than our Affiliates, subcontractors, or agents acting on our behalf in compliance with this Privacy Policy), please let us know by either:

**1\. Writing to us at:**

Collages.net, Inc.  
ATTN: Customer Service  
930 Town Center Drive  
Suite G-75  
Langhorne, PA 19047

**2\. Emailing us at:[ customerservice@collages.net](mailto:customerservice@collages.net)  
**

**Note:** If you opt-out from receiving further promotional emails from us, we will not share your email address with any third parties, including our Affiliates and partners.

**From the Company and its Affiliates**

In addition, if you also prefer not to receive further product information and promotional mailings/emails from us based on information you provided to Collages.net®, please indicate this in your instructions to us and please include your mailing address. Any email for which the primary purpose is the advertising or promotion of a product or service will contain contact information/link and a reply email address to which you may reply to opt-out from receiving similar future emails. Please note that your instructions do not govern the use of personal information you may have provided to third party merchants whose products and services may be displayed or accessible on or through the Web Site. The use of information you have provided to these third party merchants is governed by their privacy polices and terms. Also, your instructions do not apply to “transactional or relationship” email messages which include, but are not limited to, registration, order status, confirmation or reply emails. (These email messages may also contain promotional items and offers however, that is not their primary purpose.)

Your instructions will only apply to the Collages.net® Web Site, not to our Affiliates and their web sites. Please refer to the policies and opt-out provisions of those other web sites. 

Your instructions to limit the use of your information will be processed as soon as reasonably practicable and in accordance with applicable law. 

**Your Consent and Changes to this Policy**

Subject to the above provisions, by using our Web Site, you consent to the collection and use of information by us and the terms of this Privacy Policy. We may change our Privacy Policy from time to time and we will post those changes so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we may disclose it. In addition, if you would like prior notice of changes to the Privacy Policy or Terms of Use, email us at [ customerservice@collages.net](mailto:customerservice@collages.net) from the email address to which you would like notice sent. By using Collages.net®, after such changes and posting, you agree to be legally bound and to abide by the changes and other provisions contained in the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use of which this policy is a part. 

**Your Comments**

Collages.net® welcomes feedback concerning this Privacy Policy. Please send your comments and questions to [ customerservice@Collages.net](mailto:customerservice@Collages.net).  
  
Last updated on July 18, 2006  

Copyright 2007 by Collages.net Inc. [Terms Of Use](http://www.collages.net/site/Home/tabid/101/ctl/Terms/Default.aspx) [Privacy Statement](http://www.collages.net/site/Home/tabid/101/ctl/Privacy/Default.aspx)
